Finding Aid for Alexander Eckstein Papers 1943-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- University of Michigan
  - Faculty Reform Coalition
    - Council on Minority Affairs 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - Opportunity Program 1971 (Box 8)
    - University Judiciary 1971 (Box 8)
  - News Releases (Box 8)
- Vietnam
  Eckstein's interest in Vietnam grew out of his work on China, especially since American policy in Vietnam was so closely tied to the existing China policy. Thus the series Vietnam contains policy statement (by Eckstein and others who formed a Vietnam Study Group), Study Group minutes, correspondence with Representative Donald Riegle (Dem.-Michigan) material from a Congressional Briefing Session, and two folders of collected information on Vietnam.
  - Collected Materials, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Congressional Briefing Session November 28, 1967, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Policy Statements (Box 8)
  - Riegle, Representative Donald M. (Box 8)
  - Study Group Minutes October 31, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Miscellanea (Box 8)
- Writings
  The second largest series, after China, is Writings. The files include drafts, reprints, reviews, research notes and correspondence relating to the publication of Eckstein's various works. The bulk of the writings concerns China and the Chinese economy, but some of his earlier studies on the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe are included. Much of Eckstein's data on the economy of Eastern Europe was gathered immediately after the end of World War II and may be valuable in its own right. This material could be useful in a comparative study of either developing countries or of Socialist and mixed economies.
  - Comments
    - by Alexander Eckstein (Box 8)
    - for Alexander Eckstein's work
      - China's Economic Revolution (Box 8)
      - Other (Box 8)
  - Drafts, 7 folders (Box 8)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 8)
  - Permission to Repriat (Box 8)
  - Publishing Concerns
    - China's Economic Development, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - China's Economic Revolution, 1971-1977 (Box 8)
    - China Trade Prospects and U.S. Policy, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - Comparative Economics Systems, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
    - Economic Development in China, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
    - Economic Trends of Communist China, 1969-1974 (Box 8)
    - Quantitative Measures of China's Economic Output, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Others (Box 8)
  - Reprints
    - Asia 1957 (Box 8)
    - China
      - Undated (Box 8)
      - 1952-1953, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 8)
      - 1956-1960 (Box 8)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 8)
      - 1963-1967 (Box 8)
      - 1968-1976 (Box 9)
      - Encyclopedia Hebraica, article on China's economy, 1971, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Comparative Studies
      - General 1950-1970 (Box 9)
      - China/India
        - 1952 (Box 9)
        - 1954, 2 folders (Box 9)
        - 1955-1967 (Box 9)
      - China/Soviet Union 1955-1964 (Box 9)
      - China/United States 1952-1975 (Box 9)
    - Developing Countries undated (Box 9)
    - Economics (general) (Box 9)
    - Europe 1943-1955 (Box 9)
    - India 1958 (Box 9)
    - Japan (Box 9)
    - Soviet Union
      - 1955-1956 (Box 9)
      - Papers for Russian Research Center, Harvard University (Box 9)
    - United States
      - 1941 (Box 9)
      - 1943 (Box 9)
    - Vietnam 1968 (Box 9)
  - Research Notes and Materials
    - Europe, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Eastern Europe, 6 folders (Box 9)
    - Hungary (Box 9)
      folders nos. 1-3
    - Hungary (Box 10)
      (folders nos. 4-7)
  - Reviews
    - By Alexander Eckstein
      - Baran, Paul: The Political Economy of Growth, 1959 (Box 10)
      - Others 1954-1974 (Box 10)
    - Of Alexander Eckstein's work
      - China's Economic Development (Box 10)
      - China's Economic Revolution (Box 10)
      - China Trade Prospects and U.S. Policy (Box 10)
      - Communist China's Economic Growth and Foreign Trade (Box 10)
      - Comparison of Economic Systems: Theoretical and Methodological Approaches (Box 10)
      - Economic Trends in Communist China (Box 10)
      - The National Income of Communist China (Box 10)
      - Others 1955-1963 (Box 10)
- Sound Recordings
  - Audio-tapes of talks, interviews, etc.
    - Voice of America broadcast January 27, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Talk on India March 21, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Memorial service for Robert F. Kennedy June 6, 1968 (Box 10)
    - "How to trade with Red China," May 1971, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
    - Interview with Alexander Eckstein 1976, 1 audiocassettes (Box 10)
- Photographs
  - Portrait; and photograph of Chinese table tennis delegation to the United States 1970s (Box 10)